Good morning, John Kiriakou. Or Hey,
hey, sorry. Trying to get myself
situated here. Me, too. I I I We have a
brand new intro that I couldn't even
play cuz I couldn't find it. So, uh
we're all trying to get ourselves
situated. That's just how it is now.
Uh welcome to Dprogram with Ted Rall and
John Kiriakou for Halloween, October
31st, 2025.
Please like, follow, and share the show.
Uh just a reminder, we are here
deprogramming you from the mainstream BS
Monday through Friday, 9:00 a.m. Eastern
Time. Um and we are going to be here
every single day of next week, as well.
So, please tune in Please tune in. Um
just want to say this is the end of the
month, so we keep track of the uh all
the metrics and all the numbers are
still improving um month after month.
And so, uh thank you. That's thanks to
you guys. But,
uh we can't do it without your support
um financial and otherwise. So, um
thanks for that. You guys are incredibly
generous and uh means the world to us.
Um John, uh we have lots to talk about
today. Yeah, there's a lot of craziness
going on today. And for a Friday,
you know, I always say I I I got this
from the agency when I was at the agency
that Friday
Ooh.
Um we just lost John Kiriakou. So, John
is overseas. Um he's finishing out the
week. I don't think it's a secret. Uh
they're in uh the in Iberia, and he will
be back home this weekend. There's John.
We'll put him back on. I have no idea
what that was all about. I
I blame Ice and and uh
and and Israel. Why not? Yes, Israel,
too. So, I was saying Fridays at the CIA
were always very, very slow because
everything's closed in the Middle East
on either Thursday and Friday or Friday
and Saturday, depending on the country
you're in. They have different weekends.
And that sort of bled into the United
States, too. It's usually quieter on a
Friday. Congress is usually not in
session. Even when they're in session,
they're going home on on Thursday
nights.
But, man, there is so much to talk about
today. It's busy. And none of it is good
news, I hate to say. No, that's true.
And I'll just go through I'll run it
through so everybody knows what what to
expect. Um so, obviously we're talking
about the uh looming deadline tomorrow
about snap benefits, as well as the
Affordable Care Act um subsidies. All uh
hits Everything hits the wall this
weekend. Not that Congress much seems to
care. They They have They have the House
has had the has had the month off, and
the Senate has the weekend off. They're
like, "Well, you know, what? Me worry?"
Anyway, we'll get into that. Um Trump's
polls um among young voters have
absolutely fallen off a cliff. And I
don't mean like, "Oh, like, you know, in
the last 5 years." I mean, literally in
just a matter of months, Gen Z voters,
which is people under 30, uh have gone
from 50% approval to 20% approval from
February to October. I don't know that I
I don't think Richard Nixon suffered
such a drop-off in 1974.
Um No, that was more gradual.
>> And and you know you know he's concerned
because yesterday he said that his poll
numbers have never been higher, and his
poll numbers may be at a record high for
any president in American history.
I mean, you know, all true except for
not being attached to reality at all. Um
yeah, and by the way, it's not just the
Gen Z. I know uh people are watching and
saying, "But, people under 30 don't
vote." And that's true. But, this is
also true about 30-somethings, and they
do vote. Um and they've also been voting
more and more. Um the Defense Department
admitted in a classified briefing that
they don't know who they're blowing up
in the Caribbean. Um that's even some
Republican congressmen are starting to
question whether that's such a great
thing. And of course
>> that they're serial killers.
Yes, they are. That's what it comes down
to. They're mass murderers. They're
random murderers. Although, I have to
say, John, if you were a Venezuelan
fisherman,
might you not I know you have to make a
living, but might you not decide to take
like a 2-3-6-week vacation right now?
Yeah, I would. Hey, gang, can I add
something else? Talking about killing
Venezuelans and poll numbers and
protesters and all this stuff. You know,
I mentioned offhandedly last week that
um
that Stephen Miller lives in Arlington,
Virginia, where I live. He lives walking
distance from my house. And people have
been going over there for weeks and um
writing mean things in chalk on the
sidewalk in front of his house. And
there's nothing he can do about it
because the sidewalk is is public you
know, it's public thoroughfare. You can
do whatever you want.
So, he abruptly sold his house for $2.3
million. It's a nice house.
And moved.
They never told us where he moved until
today. I mentioned to you that
that I read this hyper-local
website for local news called
arlingtonnow.com.
Arlingtonnow.com says it's not just
Stephen Miller. Stephen Miller, Pete
Hegseth, and Kristi Noem all moved onto
Fort Myer Army base.
What?
>> That that abuts. Yep. And they moved
into housing that is reserved for one-
to four-star generals.
All three of them and their families.
They're I mean, talk about talk about
gated community. That's the mother of
all gated communities. Yeah, and that's
a great way to say it. It's the mother
of all gated communities. And I tell you
what, before 9/11,
because my wife and I were both GS-15s,
we were allowed membership in the
officers' club at Fort Myer. So, we used
to go go bowling,
have a beer, have a burger. We'd go to
the pool in the summer. Then 9/11 hit,
and you need a DOD ID showing that
you're either a general who lives there
or that you are assigned to the base.
So, I haven't been on that base since
9/11.
But, they're just allowed to move into
homes reserved for three- and four-star
generals, and we're all supposed to just
nod our heads.
Well, what happens when they when Trump
gets sick of them and fires them or just
let's let's assume we ever have another
Democratic president again. Um
Not not 100% certain. Um
what happens then?
I guess I guess we throw them out on
their asses.
And then and then then they have to put
up with the chalk remarks on their on
their sidewalk. The chalk
If If you chalk the sidewalks, the
terrorists have won. Yeah, exactly.
Chalk. Big baby.
>> Thank you very much, Gregory uh Batista,
for the uh very generous $20 donation
over on YouTube. Much appreciated. Much,
much, much appreciate. We've got some
questions coming in on the Rumble feed,
too.
Uh so, we should like get some of those.
And good morning to everybody uh who
Favorite Halloween candy, F U So wants
to know.
Um
Uh mine I don't really like candies, but
I remain partial to chocolate. Uh I like
milk chocolate or dark chocolate the
best. Um especially like the heavy
salted kind. Um but, they didn't really
do that in Ohio in the 1970s. And I also
like
What were those What were those things
called? The The Oh, I liked Life Savers.
The those things. I'm a boring person.
I like chocolate. Uh I prefer dark
chocolate, but I also like uh milk
chocolate. I Honestly, I'll eat anything
that calls itself chocolate except the
white chocolate. I don't like that at
all. TSTC024 has a question, too, John.
Um
Have we seen what's going on in Sudan
with the civil war that's going on? 20
to 60,000 killed so far. What are our
guys' thoughts? I mean, that's a a very
underreported story, including by us.
We've been remiss.
>> Very. Very. I was watching coverage this
morning on this French uh
channel that I've been telling you
about, France 24 it's called. Mhm. And
um the the video from Sudan is it's just
epically brutal. I mean, hundreds and
hundreds of bodies just laying,
you know, in the fields or laying in
this hospital parking lot. The um the
the government uh government-affiliated
militia attacked civilians day before
yesterday, killed at least 624 people
just in cold blood. It was a it was a
massacre.
Uh it's it's a
crime against humanity is is what it is.
Um this John reminds me a little bit of
the underreported civil war in
Tajikistan in the '90s. Yeah. A lot of
people died. By some accounts, a quarter
to a third of the population. There were
massacres, ethnic massacres all the
time. Um you know, they they ran out of
bullets at one point. And uh and so,
they would tie people together with
ropes and throw them into rivers and uh
and drown them all together. It was like
one of their things. Um and and the you
know, the the the the similarity with
Sudan is that the uh all the the These
were proxy wars that were funded by
outsiders. And as as long as long as the
money kept coming in, the war went on.
But, eventually, the proxy um sponsors,
which included the Taliban and the US
and Russia and China, like, basically
all lost interest in Tajikistan. And um
and they stopped funding funding it. And
then like basically there was a power
sharing agreement, and they had a
fragile peace. And now they've really
climbed out of the hole. Um, it took a
long time, but it but you know, they
were in a deep hole. Um, Sudan feels
like that, right? Isn't like so the
Rapid Support Forces, which is a
breakaway part of the government, um,
it's just a civil conflict within the
government. The They're supported by the
UA They're financed by the UAE, right?
And the uh Yes. the government of Sudan
is supported by Is it Cutter or I mean,
who is it?
>> yeah, it was Saudi Arabia, I think.
>> Saudi Arabia. Yeah. So So there seems to
be a Is there a Wahhabi component to
this conflict?
You know, I would personally have called
Hassan al-Turabi uh Wahhabi, and the
leaders of Sudan today are sort of the
ideological descendants of Hassan
al-Turabi. So I would say yeah, there
probably is a Wahhabi component to this.
He was a fundamentalist by anybody's
definition of fundamentalism.
John, I think we should spend a little
bit of our weekend reading up on
checking up on Sudan and doing a deeper
dive next week cuz I we we we owe
everyone on Deep Background. And and I
think I think we owe people um a
discussion about Nigeria, as well.
There's a lot of bad bad stuff going on
in Nigeria right now. All right,
sub-Saharan Africa it is next week. Uh,
FUSO, thank you for the donation. Happy
pumpkin day to you, as well. I am a
great pumpkin believer.
Uh, as a huge fan of peanuts, um, of
course so am I, as well. Um
All right, so John, we have all the We
have this panoply of of stories to
choose from. What would you like to get
into first? Ted, if you don't mind, I'd
like to start at the end and talk about
prospects for Pakistani troops
to be sent to Gaza.
Let's do it.
>> it sounds nuts, and it actually makes a
little bit of sense.
Um, and the reason is while Pakistan is
Muslim, it has always kept the
Arab-Israeli uh conflict at arm's length
because the Pakistanis are not Arabs.
They're They're Pakistanis.
And so they have enough problems
let alone to have to worry about what's
happening in Palestine, as well. So now
there are rumors that both the Israelis
and the um
Saudis are saying, "What about
Pakistan?" Now this makes a lot of sense
to me from the Saudi perspective because
Saudi Arabia and Pakistan are joined at
the hip like this.
They love each other. And the Pakistanis
make up the vast majority of the Saudi
military.
So to send Pakistanis to Gaza might
actually work out. They're Muslims,
so they should have the respect of the
Gaza Palestinians, and vice versa. They
would show respect to the Gaza
Palestinians because they understand the
culture and the and the religion.
And um
they would sort of take the air out of
uh Hamas's sails, which is exactly what
the Israelis want. I haven't seen any
comment by the United States on this,
but um
but I think this might be a good idea.
Well, so the the the rumors that are
floating are that we're they're talking
about 20,000 troops. That's a lot. Um,
of course, you know, it is a place where
2.2 million people used to live and 1.7
million people still live. Um, so it's
not that much, but I mean, it's still a
good size group. Um,
this is supposedly been brokered between
the ISI and Mossad. What's the
relationship like?
Well, there was a formal relationship as
as recently as uh 1979.
But um
there is no formal relationship since
then.
Like I say, they they don't have a lot
They don't have a lot to do with each
other in in day-to-day world events.
Um
but they're not at each other's throats.
The Pakistanis are worried about the
Indians, and to a slightly lesser
extent, they're worried about the
Afghans. They don't have time to worry
about the
about the Israelis. And the Israelis
have The Israelis have never seen
Pakistan as a threat to Israel.
You know, they'll they'll offer vocal
support for the Arabs, but that it ends
there with vocal support.
That's it.
So yeah, I mean, yeah, there I mean, you
know better than anyone there are many
different kinds of Muslims, right? So
Absolutely. Palestine So the Palestinian
Muslims, the the particularly the ones
in Gaza,
how are they going to relate to uh their
Muslim brothers from South Asia?
I mean, not to mention they're Aren't
they going to be seen as an occupation
force that is doing the bidding of the
Zionist entity?
There's always the possibility that that
would be the case, but
the Gaza Palestinians are Sunni Muslims.
The Pakistanis are almost entirely Sunni
Muslims. Handful of Shia, but they tend
not to be in the military cuz they can't
get promoted.
Um, so that that might be enough. You
know, I was thinking about this when I
first heard about it, and I was
thinking, "Well, the alternative would
have been
troops from Tahiti, right? We We've
talked about about how um or from Fiji.
We talked about how these Pacific
islands provide so many peacekeeping
forces, and it's a major source of of
income for them. It makes up a great
part of their budget.
Um
they're cultural strangers,
you know, the the people from the South
Pacific.
At least the Pakistanis would understand
Islam, would respect,
you know, Palestinian women,
all the stuff that that non-Muslim
peacekeeping forces over the years have
been accused of ignoring. will not get.
Yeah.
So they I mean, but what if they're
perceived as I mean, if this is being
framed as an ISI-Mossad deal, anything
that's seen as being related to Israel
is obviously as toxic as it can possibly
get right now.
>> but if the Saudis weigh in and endorse
it, I think that'll be good enough.
The Saudis aren't being viewed as I
mean, aren't the Saudis being viewed as
as feckless by the Palestinians? I mean,
you know, given the fact that they were
before October 7th I mean, if October
7th hadn't happened, right now there
might be an Israeli ambassador in
Riyadh.
Yeah, that's exactly right. Um, the
Bahrainis, the uh Emiratis, the
Tunisians, the Moroccans, even the
Sudanese are indeed seen as feckless
because they caved and joined the
so-called Abraham Accords. You're right,
if if there hadn't been an October 7th,
there probably would be an Israeli
ambassador in Riyadh and a Saudi
ambassador at least in Tel Aviv, if not
in Jerusalem.
But there isn't.
And so I think the Palestinians would
probably hang on that.
And then what about um, you know,
obviously these denials are coming out
of Islamabad. Um,
the Of course, you know, I always I'm
sure you're like me. I I There are
denials, and then there are and then
there are denials. And this is not a
denial denial. This is like a there we
have no such plans, which of course
means you could be working on it, indeed
have plans, but you don't, you know, you
can still credibly say until you've
pulled the trigger and the prime
minister has signed off, it's not really
a plan. It's just something we're
discussing. Yeah.
Yeah, it's true. Of course, Pakistan's
probably the most rumor-tastic country
in the world.
>> Oh my god, listen. I gave an interview
to an Indian uh outlet last week.
All hell has broken loose in South Asia.
I've I'm I have more death threats than
I can shake a stick at. And then and
then the um
what's his name? Imran Khan's
party
um issued a formal statement demanding
that I apologize to Imran Khan, I
apologize to the party, and I apologize
to the Pakistani people. And they want
it in writing by the end of the day
today. And I told them, and please
forgive me,
but I told them that I wipe my ass with
their apology, and that's as good as
they're getting.
And then the death threats came in.
Shocking. I can't say I'm surprised, but
but I would definitely have someone else
do you don't who you don't like start
your car in the morning. Um
$20 donation, thank you so much from
Unsung Pat.
Um, she's talking a little bit back to
you know, back a little echo on Sudan.
Starvation, one of the oldest weapons of
war plus poor plus desperation equals a
powder keg  napalm. Just need a
match. Looting. Sudan, 700 days of
conflict, right? 2 years. Civilians
starving. Something Irish heritage knows
well. Uh, $1 donation from FUSO. Thank
you so much. That's an Candace Owen
coverage of the Egyptian plane with the
Charlie Kirk assassination.
John, do you have Do you have such
thoughts? I don't I don't.
>> familiar with it.
Okay. Do you Do you know anything about
it? No. No, I was hoping you did. No,
I'm sorry. That was a joke.
>> uh maybe FUSO can elaborate a little bit
in the chat, and we'll try to figure
that out. Also, thank you so much over
on on
for the uh five uh five euro donation
from Roden Gu 9864 regarding the
Cameroon situation. Man, it is all about
sub-Saharan Africa.
>> it's it's it's dire over there. Aside
from being Is there Is there Do Do Do
these crises have anything in in common?
I mean, is there a
you know
economic or agricultural thing going on
right now in Africa?
>> Cameroon Cameroon less so than Chad,
Mali, and Nigeria. Chad, Mali, and
Nigeria, it's it's Al-Qaeda and its
associated groups, Boko Haram. They're
just slaughtering people, especially
Christians. And what they've been doing
is is just going into schools and
opening fire. They're kidnapping some of
the children and opening fire on the
adults, the the teachers, the
administrators, or they'll they'll herd
people into churches and then set the
churches on fire and then shoot anybody
who tries to escape from the burning
church. Lovely. Not a good situation.
And it's not it's not being covered in
the American media for some reason. No,
not not at all, for sure. Um
question from also from a donor, Zoe
LaRosa 211. Thanks for the two bucks.
Will Pakistan help Hamas though? Oh,
well, that's a good question. It's a
legitimate question. And and the
the
consensus is that they won't because the
Pakistanis
do as the Saudis tell them to do.
And if the Saudis tell them, "You're
going to go and be peacekeepers, and by
being peacekeepers, you're also going to
help Gazan society get back up on its
feet, and you've got to protect the the
Palestinians from Hamas,
then that's what they'll do.
Um won't Hamas just rule Afghan style? I
mean, they can't melt into the into the
mountains cuz there are no mountains,
but you know, I mean, they're they are
in they're completely fully embedded in
civilian society. I mean, you know, you
might be a Hamas fighter all throughout
the last two years and then be a school
teacher during the con after the
conflict is over, and you bide your time
and you wait for the call from your
commander. Of course. You're not They
don't carry identity cards that say
Hamas on it. Right? These are just
regular normal people who who have their
own roles in society besides being Hamas
fighters.
And they don't they don't they might
even go work for the Pakistanis, right?
I mean, like I met a guy
I met a guy in Afghanistan in in in
2010, and he saw no conflict between the
fact that during the day, he worked for
the Northern Alliance government of
Hamid Karzai as an irrigation expert,
and at night, he would go out with the
Taliban and blow up irrigation canals.
It's the great great cycle of life for
these people. There's no conflict in
that. Oh my god almighty.
We have a we have a question, too, about
Kimberly Guilfoyle. She arrives tomorrow
in Athens as the US ambassador to
Greece.
The Greeks the Greek media, at least,
is very excited about this. I will say
that the Greek American press is not
excited about this. But, with that said,
for reasons that I will never
understand, Donald Trump seems to love
Greece, and Greece seems to love Donald
Trump. And it doesn't matter if if
Mitsotakis is the prime minister or if
there's a socialist or or Eurocommunist
prime minister,
Trump has gotten along with all of the
prime ministers that Greece has had
during the Trump presidency. And you
know, Greece has had a mix over the
years of of career diplomats who've been
ambassador and political appointees
who've been ambassador. And they like it
when the ambassador has a direct line to
the president. So, you know, would I
have chosen Kimberly Guilfoyle? Of
course not. But but she is, you know, a
practiced seasoned attorney, former US
attorney or assistant US attorney,
and she's got a direct line to Trump.
So,
we'll see how the next 3 years go. Zizis
Karagiannis, thank you so much for the
29.99 Australian dollars. Much
appreciated. Thank you very much. Yeah,
so
yeah,
all right. So,
just like scrolling through scrolling
through. All right, so
hmm, that's so strange. There are two
shows going on, one on screen, one in
chat. Oh, well, that's true.
So, anyway,
well, that's always true in the Rumble
feed.
You know, sometimes the the Rumble feed
has nothing to do with what we're
talking about. And I'm like, do you guys
even watch? I mean, you know, hey, we're
happy to be here, but what are we,
chopped liver?
All right,
so I mean, so I I guess the thing is um
how like let's let's put this on to the
how likely o meter. I mean, I think
first of all,
if there is an international
peacekeeping force, then I could see
this being a
40% chance this could happen.
I don't think there's going to be an
international peacekeeping force, but
>> think the Israelis will allow it.
They don't want peace?
No. Yeah, I mean, look at what they've
been doing. We should talk about how
they've been [__] up the ceasefire.
Yeah.
Did you see today the Washington Post
reported that
that in a classified briefing yesterday,
the State Department said that they have
confirmed Israeli atrocities against
Palestinian civilians. Yep. Um there
have been so many of them that they
haven't been able to go through all the
different atrocities that have been
committed. So, why would the Israelis
want outsiders, especially outside
Muslims, to come in and be the
peacekeepers? Yeah, but they're still
not even allowing the media in, right?
And it's amazing to me. I mean, what do
you make of the fact that uh American
media organizations aren't complaining
and saying like, "Look, you guys didn't
let us in during the war, and you should
have, but right now there's this active
ceasefire brokered by the United States
president, and you're still not letting
American reporters in you know they're
chomping at the bit. I mean, I am. I'd
go. I mean, like so like what what's the
deal?
Yep, exactly right.
If they're not going to let American
journalists in, they're not going to let
Pakistani troops in.
Yeah. Yeah. And well, if they don't want
American journalists in there because
the mass graves are going to get are
being dug up right now.
>> Yeah. Yeah.
Uh
Yeah, it's not good. All right, so well,
I guess we probably while we're on this
on this track, do you want to talk about
the Southern Caribbean?
Yeah, let's do that. Another place where
all you can do is shake your head right
now.
Yeah, so we all know what's been going
on with it. I mean, first of all, I'm
not really clear on how these attacks
are supposed to be pressuring President
Maduro. Um I mean, if I'm President
Maduro, of course I'm displeased that my
nationals are being blown up like
they're going out of season. But um you
know, I mean, how is that like really
making him think,
"Oh, I should step I should step I
should step away, I should run away, go
into exile."
I don't see it. Why? No. No, I I agree
with you.
Uh this is a stupid policy. And now we
have confirmed what we always suspected
is that nobody even knows that these
people are drug runners or if these are
drug boats. They're they're probably
just innocent fishermen. You know, these
bodies washed up in Trinidad and Tobago
last week, or pieces of bodies washed
up, Mhm. apparently from from boats that
the that the Pentagon bombed, and they
appear to be just Trinidadian fishermen.
Can you imagine being at the beach like
with your family, and then, you know,
someone's leg washes up?
>> yeah, exactly. Another thing, too, is
the US has long accused Maduro of drug
trafficking. I think I mentioned to you,
I did a
I did an investigation when I was the
senior investigator on the Senate
Foreign Relations Committee, and part of
that investigation was drug trafficking
through Venezuela.
Um there there is some drug trafficking
through Venezuela. That is not to say
that Maduro controls it or even has any
idea when and where it's happening. What
it is is Colombian drug planes landing
in
Venezuela to, you know, pick up, to drop
off,
unload, who knows, and then continuing
on to Africa.
It's
it's not clear-cut like the
administration wants you to think it is.
And then we had this news from earlier
in the week
that the CIA tried to recruit Maduro's
pilot
so that were Maduro to flee,
ostensibly for Cuba,
the plane, instead of landing in Havana,
would land in Key West, and the DEA
would grab him and then take him to
Miami, just like we did to Noriega, and
charge him with international
drug trafficking. By the way, why not,
out of curiosity, if you're involved in
regime change, what do you give a [__]
where the deposed ruler goes? Why do you
care if they go to [__] Havana or
Russia or Saudi Arabia or Nigeria or or
or I mean, why isn't it like what is the
point of a Noriega situation? I still
don't even understand what Bush got out
of it.
I think you get the you get the
it's a trophy to put him on trial and to
say that you captured him. I was talking
about this with Doug McGregor a couple
of days ago. Colonel Doug Doug McGregor
who's very very very conservative but in
a libertarian kind of way and he said
that
he said that Maduro is not stupid. First
of all, he's not going to go anywhere
unless
the United States physically invades
Venezuela and even then
he's not stupid enough to go to Cuba
that he will likely have arranged in
advance to get to Moscow.
Now, can he can he make it to Moscow
without being intercepted by America or
its numerous allies?
That's a long trip. It's a long trip. Uh
you can ask we
we can we can ask you know Ed Snowden
about how how perilous that trip can be.
Yeah, you know thank God that he did not
make it to Ecuador.
So, the Trump administration is asking
us to
you know basically do believe something
that we know isn't true and can't be
true. They say that 70% of overdoses in
the United States are directly
attributable to fentanyl that is
processed from a cocaine that originates
in Venezuela.
And like that's just not how it works.
That's what they said.
That's not true. That's just simply not
true. No.
But I guess they're they're counting on
people not really knowing about this and
then
I got to Google that while we're talking
cuz that's preposterous. And then
congressman uh yeah, this was the this
is what they said and then like both
Democrats and some Republicans are
starting to ask questions like from the
you know they the defense or war
department or whatever the [__] it's
called now. Um they go they went into
you know they had this classified
briefing. They're supposed to be told
exactly what's going on and the you know
the DOD admitted we literally don't know
who we're killing. No, they don't know.
They don't have any idea.
Which makes can there be any legal basis
for that?
Yeah.
It's just murder. Plain and simple.
Do you think anyone will ever Do you
think like if we had like a you know
president president AOC that anyone
would ever be held accountable? I mean
no one was ever held accountable for for
CIA torture. Obama made sure of that
within a day or two of taking office.
Yeah, exactly. No one's ever held
accountable. That's just how that works.
You can do whatever the [__] you want.
No, no one's ever held accountable. Hey,
I'm looking at the DEA's fact sheet on
fentanyl right here and fentanyl is not
made from cocaine. No, period. It's
mixed with cocaine and with every other
drug that's out there. Cocaine, heroin,
um
uh
methamphetamine, it's it's mixed with
everything. Um you can even put it in a
nasal spray. 42% of all pills
confiscated at the border contain
fentanyl. 42%
>> That's insane. Yeah, and it says 42% of
all pills tested for fentanyl contained
at least 2 mg of fentanyl which is
considered to be a lethal dose.
Oh Jesus. Yeah, now I mean well this is
like I mean it's like the if you
remember the of course obviously in the
80s
angel when they when when drugs would be
spiced with angel spiked with angel dust
to make them PCP to make it a little
more interesting quote unquote. Um I
don't know you know the drug I mean I
knew quite a few serious drug addicts at
that time and I don't think they were
ever needing or desiring that. You know,
I mean honestly it's a it was a flaw in
the marketplace and I don't mean to be
dry about that. I just don't think it's
something that drug users really wanted.
You know, drug users want to know what
they're getting. Yeah, they do. Um
just like any other consumers.
My brother-in-law died of a of a
fentanyl overdose.
Um
>> Oh wow. And
you know, he didn't mean to. He thought
he was just going to smoke some meth
like he smoked every day
and um
and 15 minutes later he was dead and
that was it.
Jesus. Yeah, 36 years old. Jesus. What a
horrible I hate drugs.
Terrible.
So, um well let's talk about Should we
move on to the the to the domestic
situation? Sure thing.
All right, so tomorrow's November 1st.
Um
people are going to lose their his start
losing their health care
and poor people I guess the question is
does anyone care about poor people? But
42 million Americans are going to lose
their
food stamps snap benefits. Um
Republicans they might be singing a a
different tale but you and I both know
they're they're scared to death. There's
that poll we talked about. It's the
latest YouGov Economist poll that shows
20% of adults under age 30
liked Donald Trump a lot. Sorry, 50%
liked him a lot back in February. Now
only 20% like him
and even it's I mean and the same and
those numbers are not quite as dramatic
but pretty damn dramatic for the
30-something crowd
the millennials. Um
you know,
obviously like you said the we know the
president's nervous.
So, the big takeaway here is yes just
now
Donald Trump is calling to for the
nuclear option. So, not to not nuclear
weapons or nuclear powered missiles but
and you know by the way I want to thank
you thank the listener who pointed out
that nuclear powered missiles don't have
to be nuclear weapons themselves. Um
that's very true. We weren't clear about
that yesterday. Yeah, that's true. And
but but like so he wants basically they
want to get rid of the filibuster for
foreign
viewers the US Senate has a rule that
goes back that's been controversial for
a long time that says that basically you
can
you can
keep the you can keep the Senate in
session and basically you can't really
truly close the deal unless you get 60%
not a simple majority of the vote. You
need 60 you need 60 seats not 50 60
votes not 50 votes.
And basically what that allows is a
minority in in the Senate to gum up the
works.
Traditionally that's been the
Republicans but certainly Democrats are
doing it now and that's why we have a
shutdown. Donald Trump basically is
calling for the end of the filibuster.
That would have some dramatic long-term
political implications. I want to be
clear Democrats started this [__] when
they got they pulled the nuclear option
on Trump's on the on the Democratic
Obama's
uh
judicial nominations and they thought
literally they said oh don't worry
Republicans will never get to avail
themselves of this because Democrats
will literally be in power forever. They
literally said that. You can look it up.
>> I want to punch the corpse of Harry Reid
right in the face.
That was his idea.
Idiot. [__] idiot. So, like the point
is you know your old uh you know your
old uh your old buddy uh you know smart
guy. I mean he's he's he's working a
[__] up system. He's working a [__]
up system. He's working a [__] up
system. He's working a [__] up system.
He's working a [__] up system. He's
working a [__] up system. He's working
a [__] up system. He's working a
[__] up system. He's working
>> He's another one I want to punch in the
face. He said that Democrats have to
stop acting like children and just vote
for this budget.
Well then but then okay, so John
Fetterman who has health issues
should be able to relate to people who
have health issue who need health
insurance.
>> You would think. And so you know, I mean
he had the dude had a stroke. I mean you
know if you have a stroke I mean I
literally okay, so I have a a cartoonist
colleague
about a month ago. He's a little younger
than me. He had a stroke. His entire
right side is paralyzed. He's facing
he's about to become homeless. He posted
on Facebook that he has no idea where
he's going to go.
Um that that the rehab is about to throw
him out on the street. He has no one to
take him in or take care of him.
He can't work.
Yeah, right. Exactly.
So then what? What the rest of us
>> a you throw a dude with with a right
side of his body doesn't work. You know
John you know what I would do? I would
literally go to I would be one of those
non-violent bank robbers where you know
people have done this. They like I I
need to go to prison so I have a place
to stay and they you know they walk into
the bank they say please give me all
your money and then they wait
patiently for the police to arrive and
they say you know I I I needed to be
arrested. Please take me to prison cuz I
would be homeless. I'm I'm I have no
way out. I think I I think I told you
that one of my cellmates he was the last
the last one of my cellmates to move in.
He was from Pittsburgh.
Nice guy, perfectly normal totally
normal guy
and I asked him what he was in for and
he said oh that he had a conviction
years ago and he had already done his
time but every year at the start of
winter he intentionally violates his
probation
so that he can spend the winters
in in jail in prison. He said that um
he otherwise lives in a tent along the
Ohio River and you know it's cold in
Pittsburgh. And so he intentionally
violates. He gets sent back for 6 months
and he says I get three meals a day, I
get a warm bed and I get free medical
care. So, better to be in prison than in
a tent you know, in a van down by the
river as the old
Saturday night Live skit goes.
Yeah, I mean honestly I think it's
I think you're your old
you know colleague your old
your old buddy you know a guy.
He's
he's working a [__] up system. Yeah,
you know what he did? He was one of
these
uh carnies. You know, he ran the
carnival rides. They're all convicts and
most of them are pedophiles. So, um he
was selling drugs from the drugs from
the carnival. And because he was
crossing state lines, going from state
to state to state selling drugs, it was
a federal charge. So, he did 7 years and
he gets 10 years probation. And so,
every winter he just violates so he can
get back in.
I mean, okay, so John, I'm glad that
that with the conversation went in this
way because this is the really the big
question I wanted to ask you. So,
here's the thing. It's a factoid now,
but one eight this this crisis reminds
us and one out of every eight Americans
is on food stamps. In some states, it's
one out of four.
Ironically, Republican states. And I'm
not going to and I'm not one of those
people who's like, well, you get what
you deserve cuz you voted for these
people.
We don't even know that. Those people
might have all voted Democratic, right?
But the point is
one What does it say?
I mean, how can you be rah-rah USA
number one, what a great country we
have, let's tell other countries, you
know, let's share our values so that
they can have 1/8 of their country
living in abject poverty. By the way,
these are the This is not the whole
state of poverty, right? There's lots of
people who are working poor, who don't
qualify for food stamps, or don't want
them, don't apply for it. There's lots
of people who who are too marginal and
sleeping like outside who are not going
to get who are not in the system, also.
So, this is just a subset of the poverty
in this country, which is really more
like one out of four.
Um
So, people are I mean,
one out of eight Americans is on food
stamps. To me, I would be like, what the
[__] is wrong with our country if I'm a
if I'm a congressman or a senator? Why
are we not doing anything Why did I
mean, why is that like not a statistic
that just makes like Donald Trump
himself say, what the [__] Why does
that not make John Fetterman say, what
the [__] Why does that not make
Lester Holt say, what the [__]
>> should say, what the [__] Because he
was the mayor of Braddock, Pennsylvania,
which is one of the poorest, most
crime-ridden cities in the entire state
of Pennsylvania. He knows better.
You know, Ted, in in 2011,
sorry, 2012 in January, um I was I was
arrested in mid-January and um
just 1 week after
my arrest, I was sitting at the dining
room table with my wife and she had a
calculator and then she looked up at me
and she said,
"I don't see how we can afford to buy
food next week." Jesus.
>> And I I said, "Are we in that bad a
shape already?"
And she said, "Yeah, everything that we
have we gave to the lawyers last week
and I don't think we have enough money
for food."
So, the next day we went to the welfare
office in Arlington County and we
qualified for literally everything,
including a $90 monthly cash supplement
because she was breastfeeding.
And we had two kids at home. And I still
had two kids two other kids that I'm
paying child support for at the time.
So, we were on we were on food stamps
for 9 months
um until she finally found a job in
October of that year. And thank God for
that. Yeah.
So, so Fetterman
knows better. Fetterman should know
better. Fetterman should be saying
exactly the opposite of what he's been
saying. And not just, you know,
yesterday and today with CNN, but really
for the for the past
2 years.
And if he's not going to help
poor people
feed their families,
then, you know, maybe it's time to
primary this guy.
Well, and also, I mean, the Republican
posture, I mean, even if you're working
55 hours a week and you don't follow all
the details, right? I mean, you you hear
the Democrat the the Republicans say,
"Agree to our plan and then we will
negotiate with you afterwards."
Everyone knows that's not how anything
works, right? It's like So, I mean, I
guess the only exception to that is if
you go into the hospital to get a
operation because it's going to cost
whatever they bill you and they don't
tell you in advance. If you're like,
"Hey, how much is this appendectomy is
going to be?" They can't They literally
can't tell you. They literally won't
tell you. It's literally like,
it's like you get the bill and you pay.
Tough [__] Sucks to be you. If you If
you can't If you have to ask, you can't
afford it.
Yep, that is it. Unsung Pat is making an
important point here that in 1973, the
wealth gap was the smallest and the
middle class was the strongest. First of
all, God bless Richard Nixon and his
economic policy, number one.
Number two,
starting with Dwight Eisenhower and
going through Nixon,
tax rates were the highest against the
wealthiest people.
And so, I mean, of course, you had the
same write-offs and such that that that
you know, we see today, but the the
basic
uh
tax rate for the wealthiest people was
upwards of 75%
and they could whittle it down from
there. Well, now they pay almost nothing
to begin with
and whittle it down from there.
And then we can't understand why our
deficits are so enormous and why there's
such a
wealth gap.
That's why there's a wealth gap. I'm
glad you brought up Richard Nixon, who,
just to be clear, was exactly the kind
of president who I was supposed to and
did hate at the time. But
but, you know, honestly, I remember wage
and price controls, my mother was making
$8,500 a year as a school teacher and
and you know, the price of sugar was
five was $5 for 5 lb, which was a lot at
the time.
>> I remember the sugar crisis. And when
wage and price controls kicked in,
thanks to Richard Nixon,
uh my mom said, "I hate that man. I hate
the Vietnam War. I hate him.
Uh but, you know, he saved my life. I
don't know how we would survive if not
for these price controls." There's a
conspiracy theory, I'm sure you've heard
it. It's actually, you know, kind of
percolates pretty high into among
historians that um Watergate was really
kind of orchestrated by the, you know,
corporate powers that be as a sort of
coup d'état to get rid of Richard Nixon
cuz they were so pissed about wage and
price controls.
>> price controls. You know, one of my
earliest memories, my dad came home one
day, I think I was four. My dad came
home one day and he said to my to my
mom, "Honey, I got a raise."
And she said, "You did?" And he shows
her this letter.
And he was making $6,800 a year. And
then I remember my mom saying, "Just
imagine, honey, if you could make 7,000,
we'd be on easy street."
You know, John, I I was in a similar
situation. I made $10,000 a year
working at Bear Stearns in 1984-85
as a trader trainee. And I calculated
that if my boss cut my pay by $12 a
month uh $12 a
Yeah, $12 a pay period, that I could get
food stamps. I called the food stamp
office. So, I went to my boss and I
asked him to cut my pay.
He was like, "Get the [__] out of my
office."
That's fantastic. And then and then that
but we were all so snotty about it. He
would come come around with the
paychecks, the paper paychecks, and it's
like, you know, you know, here you go,
blah blah blah.
And I There were guys who'd be like,
"Drop it in the trash." Like,
it's not worth it. It's not worth
waiting in line at the bank.
You know, I remember that, too, that
they used to even at the CIA, they would
just come with our our paychecks and
flip them upside down and leave them on
our chairs.
Yeah. I I I remember a couple things
about the CIA. Not to get too far off
the subject, but I was talking to a
former CIA
colleague of mine and I said, "You know,
when I started at the CIA, you could
smoke at your desk."
And then like after a a year, they made
designated smoking areas. So, all of all
the managers made their offices
designated smoking areas. Wow, so the
smoking was that big then? Oh, it was
that big, yeah. And then there's a
there's a barber in the basement of the
CIA. And when I first
when I first joined, I was like, oh, I
might as well just go get a haircut at
the CIA barber instead of going halfway
across town. And and I went down there
and they had Playboys and Penthouses all
over the uh the barber shop. Inside the
CIA.
That's that's
Yeah, it's like a whole city in there,
right? Yeah, yeah, it is. And do Do
people avail themselves of like the dry
cleaner or whatever? Oh, yeah, yeah,
everybody does. There's even a little
post office substation in there so you
don't have to go into town to mail
stuff. Oh, I would love that. Yeah, it's
great. I used to use it all the time.
God, the post office, don't even [__]
get me started there.
It's like, what a [__] disaster. And
I'm a huge I'm I'm really on team post
office, too. And like,
yeah.
Anyway.
>> my sister's husband is a is a mailman
and he finally retired in March. He said
the place is just in chaos. He just
can't do it anymore. He did 30 years,
that's the end of it.
Yeah, I do not blame.
Um
I forget Pras Michel says, I forgot
which president, but Nixon called it
closing the gold standard gold window or
whatever it was a consequence of a 1960s
president doing some other econ policy
change. Can't remember what it
specifically.
I thought it was this it was 1973,
right?
When Nixon
>> it was Nixon. Yeah, I remember gold was
like $35 an ounce or $38.
>> Yeah, it was set at $35 an ounce.
>> Yeah.
Yep.
I wish I bought like I had I wish I had
just Well, I mean I was 10 years old.
I had a I had a paper route. I could
have I could have bought gold.
Yeah.
Yeah, that's right.
Man. All right.
>> are you talking about? Yeah, oh for as
Matassa says I also don't I also I don't
even blame him for Watergate. DNC
deserve DNC deserved it and Bob Woodward
is a Navy Intel non-journalist. But
spying on Pentagon Papers guy Ellsberg
true American patriot I think is what he
was trying to say. Yeah. Autocorrect. I
hate autocorrect. I have a colleague who
is a very famous lesbian cartoonist. If
you know anything about cartooning, you
know who I'm talking about. And well,
I'll just tell you it's Alison Bechdel.
She of the Bechdel test. She did Fun
Home. And anyway, she So I was texting
her about something and it
I literally used the word pencil. You
know, as a cartoonist, you use the word
pencil. And it autocorrected thank God
before I hit send I hit I hit I caught
it before I hit send to penis. And I'm
like I do not want to be the guy who
emails who texts the word penis. Like,
"Hey, did you check out my penis?"
Oh my god.
Why is like does autocorrect think that
penis is a more often used word than
pencil?
>> I know, right?
I don't think so.
Anyway.
>> Oh my god.
So yeah, so what So what's Yeah, I mean
obviously we're heading into this Well,
let's talk about this Let's talk about
the
the nuclear option. So
what would be
How would that look? How How could the
filibuster be eliminated? Ironically,
couldn't the Democrats filibuster
that or could it be Is there another
parliamentary maneuver? No, yeah, it's a
decision made solely by the majority
leader.
There doesn't have to be a vote on it
because it's not a law. It's an internal
rule.
You know, and this was also dangerous
when Harry Reid lifted the filibuster
used the nuclear option on um
on judges.
He said, "Well, it's going to be fine."
And but he wouldn't listen to to reason
when people said, "Wait a minute, the
Republicans are going to be able to
force through their judges if you use
the nuclear option now." No, no, it's
going to be fine. They're never going to
be in the majority ever again because
you know, we're so great. And then of
course, the Republicans took the Senate.
If Donald Trump demands that John Thune
use the nuclear option and he does it,
Donald Trump is going to get his budget
for a year or two or even three maybe,
but when the Democrats
control the White House and the Senate
and you know it's going to happen
because it always does
the Democrats are going to be able to do
anything they want.
So this is an extraordinarily
short-sighted pronouncement from Donald
Trump that Thune has to use the the
nuclear option. Will he do it?
I doubt it. Thune is not a big Trump
fan. He he'll say the right things to
keep the MAGA people off his back, but
he's not a big fan of Trump and Thune
has a better historical understanding of
why the Senate needs to keep
the filibuster. It's to preserve the
rights of the minority and he knows that
they're going to be in the minority
again.
Obviously, yeah, no question. I mean,
you know, could happen relatively soon,
not next year, but it definitely, you
know, I think could happen in
three years for sure.
No question.
>> Yeah, not not next year, but it could
happen in three years, absolutely.
That's how I mean, that's the thing is
like right the Senate's all about the
long game, right? I mean, these are
people with six-year terms.
It's it's a institution with long
historical memory. People who serve it's
not at all weird or unusual to serve for
decades. So they know that like you
know, Donald Trump's there now, but
Donald Trump won't be there for for
forever.
Um
yeah, I mean just I mean, obviously they
I mean, yeah.
I if I were the Republican Republican
senators, I'd be very very nervous about
this.
But I guess the thing is John, is isn't
it a little unusual in parliamentary
systems even in bicameral ones to have
an equivalent of the filibuster where
>> Yeah. I mean, obviously we don't have
the Mr. Smith Goes to Washington thing
anymore where you stay you know, even
when Corey Booker did it it was kind of
fake and he was doing it to
but you know, you know, having to wear
the astronaut diaper and piss in your
pants or whatever you do. Right.
But like still it's an unusual
situation, right? To not have a simple
majority prevail. It is. You know, and
and it evolved. It's not in our
constitution. It evolved over time. Um
you know, I mean, what are the pros and
cons of having obviously minority rights
you know, you can't run roughshod over
the minority and you want to have
policies not just squeak through. You
want them to have a be based on broader
consensus than 50%. Yes. Right now you
can really see it the the importance of
that.
And on the downside it uh
it
Well, in in my mind to tell you the
honest to God's truth, I I don't see a
downside. It protects the rights of the
minority. On the downside it it also
leads to gridlock. And yeah, and
obstructionism. There's that.
Obstructionism, sure. Like for example,
yeah, I mean it it's true that what the
Republicans were doing to Obama's judges
was really wrong. Yeah, it was. And and
what that evil [__] Mitch McConnell
did by denying Obama his his final
Supreme Court nomination. The Democrats
it may take years, but the Democrats are
going to get revenge for that.
Although
you know, and I agree with you for 100%
but
I know I also don't forgive Obama for
kick for kicking off to uh for kicking
off to Martha's Vineyard while that was
all happening and just like, "I'm good.
See you later. See you in 6 weeks. It's
all fine. Whatever. Hillary will win."
Remember? He said that. "Hillary will
win." So it'll all be taken care of.
That was the other thing, right? That's
right. I'm not worried about the
election results. Easy peasy. We all
woke up on election morning and Nate
Silver had a had a we had a had had her
chances of winning at 90%.
You could like watch that.
>> I remember that 90%. I remember Nate
Silver having to eat crow afterwards.
>> I can't believe that guy even still has
a job after that.
I mean, think about the [__] Think about
the [__] we
you know, you got like you're getting
death threats over that thing with the
Pakistanis. I mean, Nate Silver he
really [__] up and nothing happened.
He really did.
I mean, probably
Let's talk about this judge. I mean, so
today I don't know if this may have even
be happening while we're on the air
right now. But this judge yesterday
signal signaled that Indira Talwani is
not does not believe the Trump
administration's um
basically argument. They don't want to
release the emergency funds.
There's 5.3 billion that Congress set
aside in case there was a problem paying
out SNAP. Now to be clear, that will not
cover the month of November.
It would So the government was arguing
that it would be a logistical nightmare.
I'm like really you guys have trouble
with pro rata? You guys can't say you
guys don't know the arithmetic of 5.3
billion divided by whatever the normal
November is thing
equal such percent
and that's how much you get? I don't
know if I trust this government to send
people out to outer space. But okay.
That said, they you know, the they the
government was saying, "Well, it's only
meant to be released if as a
supplement." But it's like an emergency
fund isn't a supplement. It makes So the
judge is is going to overrule. Will the
administration ignore her or appeal to
SCOTUS or Oh yeah, they'll they'll
appeal they'll appeal quickly. Which is
funny because
they make no singular of the fact that
they're that they're trying to create a
cutout to pay
servicemen and women.
Their their salaries. Forget the poor
people.
They want the military people to get
their pay.
But yeah, I
I I I think it's going to be
I think it's going to be going to be an
issue and that the administration's
going to challenge it. They'll appeal
either to the the circuit court or
they'll go straight to uh
to the Supreme Court.
And what will the So I guess the
question is is it will the Supreme Court
say, "This is an administration
prerogative and they can do what they
want" or will they
you know, it's just so hard to say.
I yeah, I mean, you know my my position
on
feeding poor people. But I I'm not sure
that she has the authority to do this.
Okay, so I guess the next question is I
mean, of course there's the broader
question if if Congress allocate
you know, allocates funds, do they have
to spend it? We're out of time
unfortunately, but we will have we'll
know by Monday what's happening what the
the and what the results look for look
like. For those of you who are facing
this
cut this this cut off, I'm very sorry
and and and ashamed of our country. I
just want to say that.
Anyway, thanks everyone for liking,
following, sharing the show.
We're Deprogrammed with Ted Rall and
John Kiriakou. We're here Monday through
Friday 9:00 a.m. Eastern Time. Stay
tuned. We will be I'll be I'll be
staying on the air with Manila Chan with
the TMI show. We'll be having a special
Halloween thing talking about
America's love affair with horror
movies.
Thanks everyone. Bye John. See you
later.
>> Bye Ted.
[Music]